这完全是惊悚片里的场景
This is straight out of a slasher flick.
通常会发现死者躺在这样的走廊尽头
Usually find murder victims at the end of hallways like these.
难以置信阿丽克西斯住在这里
Cannot believe Alexis lives here.
理查德  阿丽克西斯和派邀请我们吃晚餐
Richard, Alexis and Pi have invited us for dinner.
这对他们而言是很大的一步
This is a big step for them.
不要挑三拣四的
So let us not be judgmental.
好吧
Fine.
再说
Besides...
难道你忘了你大学时住的茅屋吗
remember the hovel you lived in in college?
唯一的区别是我没和派同居
Only difference is I wasn't shacking up with Pi.
你保持开明的态度真好  亲爱的
Well, it's nice that you're keeping an open mind, dear.
你们来了
You're here!
快进来吧  我好想向你们展示我们的温馨小屋
Come on in. I'm so excited for you to see our place.
进来吧
Come on.
天啊  你的第一个公寓
Oh... my. Your first place.
你好  C先生
Hey! Mr. C.!
欢迎  准备好
Welcome. And prepare yourself
吃上一顿美味实惠的晚餐吧
for some savory and sustainable dining.
让我猜猜  会有水果
Ah, let me guess. There will be fruit.
我会把你变成果食主义者的  C先生
I'll make a fruitarian out of you yet, Mr. C.
-太棒了  - 这是一份小小的乔迁礼物
- Great. - Uh, here is a, um, little housewarming present.
它需要阳光
And it needs sunlight,
而且还有一张小贺卡
and there's a little gift card as well.
谢谢你  奶奶
Thank you, gram.
你觉得怎么样
Well? What do you think?
我觉得很不错
Oh, I think it's adorable.
我喜欢你们做的装修
I love what the two of you have done with this.
是啊  我们装修时很开心
Yeah, we've had lots of fun fixing it up.
我们坐在毯子上吃东西
We were eating on a blanket on the floor,
然后我们发现了这扇旧门  然后把它做成了桌子
but then we found this old door and set it up as a table.
我在餐馆附近的垃圾桶里发现了椅子
And I found the chairs next to a restaurant dumpster.
垃圾桶里的椅子  那真是
Oh! Dumpster chairs. That's...
太棒了
great.
波西米亚式生活
Well, there is nothing like
最能促进血液循环了
la vie boheme to get the blood flowing.
给我吧
I'll take that.
友好点
Be nice.
瞧
Oh, look.
蒲团
A futon.
真爽
Oh, yes.
如果你们想要坚实的座位
You know, if you guys want something real to sit on,
我仓库里还有一个旧沙发  我可以...
I have an old couch in storage. I could just--
我说不好  C先生
Hmm. Uh, I don't know, Mr. C. Um...
那是什么颜色的
What color is it?
免费的
Free.
爸爸  我们不用  需要的我们都有了
Dad, we're fine. We have everything we need.
派  阿丽克西斯告诉我你找了份新工作
So, Pi, Alexis tells me that you have a new job.
是的  我在为非政府组织
I do indeed. I am tracking bee populations in the city
追踪蜜蜂种群
for an N.G.O.
这和我在哥斯达黎加做的工作很像
It's a lot like the job I did in Costa Rica.
我们在评估蜂群的能力和数量
We're assessing the colony's strength and numbers.
就是说你负责数蜜蜂
So you're... counting bees.
不止如此  C先生
Well, there's a little more to it than that, Mr. C.,
但  是的
but... yeah.
那是份真正的工作
And that's a real job?
对  是真正的工作
Yes, it's a real job.
蜜蜂对食物供应来说很重要
Bees are vital to the food supply.
这是重要的工作
It's important work.
好吧
Well...
只要这工作能让你们买得起水果摆桌上就好
so long as it puts fruit on the table.
说到桌子  我饿坏了
Speaking of the table, I am famished.
我们可以开餐了吗
Shall we dine?
好  开饭吧
Yes, let's do that.
不用说  晚餐是一场灾难
Needless to say, dinner was a disaster,
但真正的灾难是
but the real disaster is that
阿丽克西斯和他同居了
Alexis has moved in with this guy.
他根本配不上她
He's just so wrong for her.
她会想明白的
Yeah, well, she'll figure it out.
至少她没住在脏地方  那很好
At least she's not living in squalor. That's good.
不  可不好  我倒希望是脏地方
No, it's not good. I was hoping for squalor.
我指望是脏地方
I was counting on squalor.
因为阿丽克西斯受不了脏地方
Because Alexis cannot last in squalor.
我希望同居风波赶紧过去
I was just hoping this whole thing would blow over.
她会发现派是没有野心的嬉皮士
She would see Pi for the ambition-free hippie
而他现在变成了不着调的新世纪十字军
that he is, and now he's morphed into some kind of new age crusader.
就好像是他把做一个迷人的男孩变成了一种职业
It's as though he's turned being a charming man-child into a career.
那听起来还真是"不耳熟"啊
Yeah, that doesn't sound familiar, does it?
我需要一起超赞谋杀案  这样我就不会纠结那事了
What I need is a good murder so I can stop obsessing.
我们满足你的要求  卡塞尔
Well, we got one for you, Castle.
死者名叫苏珊娜·里奇兰德  28岁
Our victim is Susannah Richland, 28.
名片上写着她是会计
Business card says she's an accountant.
会计怎么会搞成这样
How does an accountant end up like this?
很恐怖吧
Freaky, huh?
看看她手上的标记  看起来像圣痕
Look at those marks on her hand. They look like stigmata.
她摆的姿势像是被钉在十字架上
Yeah, the way she's posed might suggest a crucifixion.
不过死因
Except the cause of death
是喉咙上的刺伤
is probably that stab wound to the throat
-这是双刃剑造成的  比如说匕首  -匕首
- from a double-edged blade like a dagger. - A dagger?
也许这是某种仪式性献祭
Maybe this is some kind of ritualistic sacrifice.
也许是凶手故意为之
Or maybe the killer wanted to make it look like it was.
由于现场缺少血迹  我认为她是在别处被杀
Note the lack of blood. I'd say she was moved here
然后移到这里来的
but killed somewhere else.
我能不能推测是祭坛
Might I suggest a sacrificial altar?
不行
No, you may not.
死亡时间
Do we have a time of death?
我推断是晚十点到午夜
I'm thinking 10:00 to midnight.
好吧  我开始排查
All right, uh, I'll start a canvass
收集监控录像
and start gathering security video,
看有没有人目睹了弃尸过程
see if I can find someone who witnessed the body drop.
联系联调局
Yeah, and get ahold of the FBI,
看他们那里有没有相同作案手法的凶杀案
see if they have any other murders with the same M.O.
-好  -刚跟苏珊娜的老板通完电话
- Yeah, okay. - Just got off the phone with Susannah's boss.
他想不明白她怎么会遇害
He knows of nothing in her life that would explain this.
但他说她最近行为举止有些怪异
But he did say she'd been acting odd lately
她还请了一周假
and that she'd asked for a week off
去处理私事
to handle a personal matter.
他知道是什么私事吗
And he didn't know what it was?
不知道  她的同事也都不知道
No. Neither did any of her co-workers.
联系死者的家人朋友
All right, contact her family and friends.
看他们知不知道
Let's see if they knew.
-我和卡塞尔去她家  -好的
- Castle and I are gonna go to her apartment. - All right.
你知道她最近
Did you know of any personal matters
在处理什么私事吗
she might have been dealing with?
不知道  但肯定出事了
No, but something was up.
上周开始  她的作息变得很不规律  经常晚归
Last week, she started keeping odd hours, staying out too late.
不是她的风格
It wasn't like her.
她家里来客人吗  有男朋友吗
Did she have any visitors, any men in her life?
我没见过
Not that I ever saw.
-查完记得锁门  -谢谢
- Be sure to lock up when you're done. - Thanks.
一位看起来普通的会计
An apparently ordinary accountant
被残忍杀害  尸体根据仪式摆放
brutally slain and ritually posed,
被害前忙于处理私事
all while tending to a personal matter
行迹诡秘
shrouded in secrecy.
哪有诡秘
It's not shrouded in secrecy.
只是还不知道是什么事而已
We just don't know what it is yet.
我的版本更具戏剧色彩
My version has more dramatic flair.
她家有很多有关中世纪史的书籍
She's got a lot of books here on medieval history.
也许她的阴暗秘密
Maybe her dark secret
跟黑暗时期[欧洲中世纪]有关系
has something to do with the Dark Ages.
那就解释了她尸体的姿势
That could explain the way we found her body.
卡塞尔  可能让你说对了
Castle, you might be on to something.
看这个
Look at this.
宗教图标和异教符号
Religious icons and pagan symbols.
她是最近才迷上这种东西的
This fascination of hers is recent.
这些书都是三天前从图书馆借出的
All these books were checked out of the library three days ago.
那跟她的凶杀案有什么关系
Okay, so what does that have to do with her murder?
我可能知道答案
I think I know the answer.
五角星形  灵眼
The pentagram, the all-seeing eye--
都是黑魔法中的供能对象
both of those are power objects in dark magic.
这些元素  土  气
All these elements-- earth, air,
火  水  以太  都是
fire, water, ether-- all medieval symbols
与邪恶法术有关的中世纪符号
that are sometimes associated with satanic practices.
苏珊娜迷上了神秘学
Susannah was into the occult.
神秘学  我了解我表妹
The occult? I know my cousin.
她不会跟这种事扯上关系的
No way was she mixed up with that kind of thing.
我们在她家找到了这些符号  柯林斯先生
Well, we found these symbols at her place, Mr. Collins,
以及有关中世纪史的书籍
along with some books on medieval history.
知道她怎么会有这些东西吗
Any idea why they'd be there?
不知道  她很热衷历史
No. I mean, she was a history buff,
但多是美国历史  不是那种
but more American history, not that kind of thing.
她跟人结过怨吗  柯林斯先生
Did she have any, uh, enemies in her life, Mr. Collins?
或者情感危机
Any relationship issues?
应该没有
Not that I know of.
我不明白谁会杀害她
I just--I don't understand who would do this to her.
你最后一次见她是什么时候
When was the last time you saw her?
大概  三周前吧
Maybe... three weeks ago.
我是她唯一的亲人
I was her only family,
所以我们每隔几个月就一起共进晚餐
so we'd get together for dinner every few months.
但奇怪的是  她
But it's strange. She, um...
她昨晚突然给我打电话
She actually called me last night out of the blue.
她说什么了
And what did she say?
她说有些话要跟我说
That she had something that she wanted to talk to me about.
什么话
What was that?
我还没来得及问
I didn't even get a chance to ask.
她被人打断了
She got interrupted or something,
说回头打给我
said she'd call me right back,
却她没回电
but she never did.
现在我知道原因了
But now I know why.
联调局数据库里没有符合本案
So the FBI doesn't have any murders in their database
作案手法的凶案
that match this M.O.
那就剩我的理论了
Which leaves us with my theory--
死者想涉猎黑魔法
our victim was dabbling with black magic,
却召唤来了恶魔
and she conjured up a demon.
或者她跟某个隐晦的宗教派别发生了冲突
Or maybe she ran afoul of some obscure religious sect,
-他们将她献给了自己的异教神  -你在干什么
- and they sacrificed her to their pagan deity. - What are you doing?
瞎编乱造  跟你一样
Making stuff up, just like you do.
那是我的工作
Yeah, because that's my job.
你得追查证据
It's your job to follow the evidence.
你这是在破坏自然秩序
You're messing with the natural order of things.
伙计们  过来看点东西
Hey, guys? Something you need to see.
现场排查没找到
So our canvass couldn't come up with anyone
目睹弃尸的人  但苏珊娜
who witnessed the body dump, but Susannah had
口袋里有张交通卡
a metrocard in her pocket.
我让纽约大都会运输署查了记录
So I had M.T.A. run its history.
她的卡昨晚在一辆M3公交车上刷过
Her card was swiped last night on an M3 bus.
她8点45分在家附近上车
She got on it at 8:45 near her apartment.
去哪
Where was she going?
公交车摄像头拍到她出现在华盛顿高地的
Bus cam has her exiting at West 168th Street
168西街
Washington Heights.
那离陈尸现场就半英里左右
That's about a half mile from where her body was found.
她去那里干什么
What was she doing way up there?
不知道
I don't know.
但我查了附近十个街区的交通监控录像
But I checked traffic cam footage in a 10-block radius,
发现苏珊娜在173西街
and I found Susannah crossing St. Nicholas
穿过圣尼古拉斯街
at West 173rd Street.
看来还有人跟着她
And it looks like she had company.
-修道士  -看下时间戳  10点05分
- A monk? - Check out the time stamp-- 10:05,
-就在死亡时间区里  -被刻意摆放过的尸体
- right in our time-of-death window. - A posed body,
神秘的中世纪符号  现在又来了个凶残的修道士
mysterious medieval symbols, and now a murderous monk.
现实版的《达芬奇密码》啊
It's a real life "Da Vinci code."
这人的身份我们有线索吗
Do we have any idea who this guy is?
我来告诉你他是谁吧
I'll tell you who he is.
他是一个刺客团体的成员
He's part of a brotherhood of assassins,
被选中去保卫一个古老的秘密
chosen to guard an ancient secret.
-卡塞尔  -跟踪一个对中世纪符号着迷的女人
- Castle...  - stalking a woman obsessed with medieval symbols?
这就是证据显示出的事实
This is what the evidence suggests.
他的脸有更清楚点的镜头吗
Can we get a closer look at his face?
他没抬过头
He never turns his head.
等等  把他头顶放大
Wait. Zoom in on his scalp.
那儿  看到了吗
There. You see that?
宗教印记
Ritual markings,
是对一些不虔诚行为的惩罚
Left by some unholy initiation.
更像是外科手术的疤痕吧
They're more like surgical scars.
我去查查一些医疗程序  看有没有
I'll see if I can look into a medical procedure
能造成这种疤痕的  也许能帮我们确定他的身份
that could cause this. Might help us I.D. him.
我跟你说  修道士  被害人  还有这些符号
I'm telling you, our monk, our victim, and these symbols
彼此是由联系的
are all connected.
我打赌苏珊娜·里奇兰德破译了这些符号
I'm betting Susannah Richland decoded these symbols
发现了一些黑暗的  尘封已久的秘密
and uncovered some dark, long-held secret,
于是付出了生命的代价
paid for it with her life.
听着  卡塞尔  我同意她最近
Look, Castle, I agree that her recent interest
对于这些符号的无端痴迷
in all things medieval
也许和案情有关  但这并不意味着
may be relevant, but it doesn't mean
她是因为某些狗血事件而被害
that she was killed in some baroque plot.
要我就不会那么肯定
Well, I wouldn't be too sure about that.
关于《达芬奇密码》的说法  卡塞尔可能说对了
Castle might be right about this "Da Vinci code" thing.
别蹬鼻子上脸
Don't... ruin it.
苏珊娜的电话记录显示
According to Susannah's phone records,
她死前当天曾给哈德逊大学的
she made a call to a professor Jason Byford
杰森·拜福德教授打过电话
at Hudson University the day before she died,
还有更劲爆的
and get this.
他是古代语言和符号的专家
He's an expert in ancient languages and symbology.
就像影片中的汤姆·汉克斯
Just like Tom Hanks in the movie.
不是狗血事件  这明明是畅销书的情节
It's not a baroque plot. It's a bestseller plot.
最起码  他应该能告诉我们
Well, at the very least, he should be able to tell us
苏珊娜到底目的何在
what Susannah was up to.
我和卡塞尔去找他聊聊
Castle and I will go talk to him.
另外  我需要你去一趟陈尸间
In the meantime, I need you to go to the morgue.
-蕾妮说她有发现  -好
- Lanie says she has something.  - Okay.
我终于确定凶器是什么了
So I was finally able to identify the murder weapon.
你之前不是说是把匕首吗
Thought you said it was a dagger.
我知道我说过什么
I know what I said, but based on
但从伤口的弧度和她颈部的伤痕来看
the curvature of the wound and the injuries to her neck,
被害人是被一把剑刺死
our victim was stabbed with a sword.
-剑  -没错  类似这样的双刃剑
- A sword?  - Yes, a double-edged sabre like this...
剑柄在她颈部留下了淤痕
With a hilt that left a crenelated bruising pattern on her neck.
还真复古啊
Very old school.
我仔细查看了她手部的伤痕
I took a closer look at her hand injuries,
发现了一些东西
and I found something.
她手掌的伤口中有墨水的残留
There was ink residue in this wound on her palm.
我根据下层真皮留下的痕迹画出了这个
I was able to draw it up from the lower dermis.
看起来是她在手上画了这个符号
It looks like she drew this symbol on her hand.
我得把这个给贝克特看看
All right. I gotta get this to Beckett.
我得赶紧回局里了
Head back to the precinct.
是的  我见过苏珊娜
Yes, I met with Susannah.
经常有人打来问一些研究问题
People often call with research questions,
我希望能帮上忙
so I try to be helpful.
她想知道这些符号的含义
She wanted to know what these symbols meant.
-你怎么说的  -我说要视情况而定
- What did you tell her?  - I said that it all depends.
这些符号有的已经存在上千年了
Some of these have existed for thousands of years.
在不同的文化中有着不同的含义
They signify different things to different cultures.
这些符号与危险的东西有关的吗  比如邪教
Are any of them tied to anything dangerous, like cults?
是有一些
Hmm, a few, yes,
不过大部分都与共济会有关
but mostly, these are associated with the freemasons,
所以在美国的建筑和图标中才会这么常见
which is why you see so many on buildings and icons in the U.S.
我们的很多开国元勋都是共济会成员
A lot of our founding fathers were freemasons.
我知道  我看过《国家宝藏》
Yes. I saw "National treasure."
我也是  真遗憾
As did I, sadly.
不少可恶的事实错误
Some odious factual errors.
不过在美国独立战争期间
Though it is true that during the american revolution,
的确有些类似的符号
symbols like these were used as markers
被用作战争机密和掩埋宝藏的标记
for war secrets and buried treasure.
宝藏
Treasure?
比如英国战败后
Like the British gold left behind
留下的那些金币  或是美国国库首批铸造的钱币中
when they lost the war or the missing half dimes...
遗失的那一半
the first coins minted by the U.S. Treasury.
教授  苏珊娜问过你这个符号吗
Professor, did Susannah ask you about this symbol?
应该没有  怎么了
I don't believe so. Why?
她昨晚被杀了
She was killed last night,
我们认为所有这些符号都与之相关
And we believe all of these symbols are relevant.
被杀
Killed?
怎么了
What is it?
有些东西你们得看看
Uh, um, there's something you need to see.
她带着这封信来的
She had this letter with her.
她想知道它是否能与这些符号联系起来
She wanted to know if it was connected to the symbols.
我从没见过这类东西
Now I'd never seen anything quite like it,
所以我...
so I, uh, I, um,
我趁她不注意的时候偷拍了一张照片
well, I snuck a picture of it while she wasn't looking.
"我  纽约城的西奥多·罗斯
"I, Theodore Rose, of New York City,
"一个身心健康的忠诚爱国者
"a loyal patriot of sound mind and body,
...这将成为我的临终遗嘱"
do the..to make this my last will and testament."
西奥多·罗斯是十八世纪的著名石匠
Theodore Rose was an 18th-century stonemason
不过这可不只是一份遗嘱
of some renown, but it's more than a will.
继续读  这里
Keep reading. Here.
"我将把钥匙传给后世
"So I pass to them still living this key
"它将指向我们的大秘密
"which marks the way to our great secret,
藏在城市之中
enshrined within the city."
而这封信就是找到它的关键
And this letter is the key to finding it.
她从哪里搞到这信的
Where did she get it?
她没说  不过从日期和封印上看
She didn't say, but according to the date and seal,
这信写于1798年
It was written in 1798.
那些拉丁文是什么意思
And the latin phrases-- what do they mean?
我帮她翻译了其中的一些
Well, I translated some of them for her.
貌似是某种谜语  这一句说
They're riddles of some kind. This one says
世界在天堂与埃土中翻转
"The world turns between the heavens and the ash heap."
这不是谜语  而是线索
They're not riddles. They're clues--
有关共济会宝藏的线索
Clues leading to some great masonic treasure.
最后一句话也许就是她遇害的原因
And this last line could be why she was murdered.
危险和灾难
"Periculum et dolor..."
我的拉丁文不太灵光  但这句应该是说
My latin is pretty rusty, but I think that means
谁若心生歹意
"Peril and woe to him who follows this path
必将遭遇不幸
with a dark heart."
-我是贝克特  -那个修道士
- Beckett. - So that pattern
头上的伤疤是一种叫
of scars on our monk's dome was from a procedure called
脑立体定向术留下的
stereotactic brain surgery.
能查到他是谁吗
Okay, can that get us an I.D.?
医疗记录应该是保密的吧
Because medical records are confidential.
但监狱记录就不用保密了
Prison records aren't.
我猜测他入过狱
I took a shot that our guy did some time.
系统中有19个人曾动过这手术
19 men in the system had this surgery,
但只有一人的伤疤与这修道士
but only one had scars that were an exact match
完全吻合  本杰明·韦德
to the monk-- Benjamin Wade.
他在格林黑文坐牢期间
He got surgery to remove a tumor
为移除脑瘤做了这项手术
while doing a stretch at Green Haven
罪名是谋杀未遂
for attempted murder.
听到了吗  卡塞尔
Hear that, Castle?
嫌犯是前科犯  凶恶的修道士
Our suspect is an ex-con-- a felonious monk.
贝克特  没找到本杰明·韦德现在的住址
Hey, Beckett, got no current address on Benjamin Wade,
但他入狱之前在布朗克斯
but he did have an apartment in the Bronx
有一间公寓
before he got sent to the joint.
去查下  看谁知道他现在住哪
Okay, check it out. See if anyone knows where he is now.
我估计这里没人知道韦德的消息
I don't think anyone here can give us a line on Wade.
当地警察说这里都被
Local P.D. Says this place has been taken over
流浪汉和瘾君子占满了
by squatters and crackheads.
看看这地方
Look at this place.
这空气吸一口都能让人得肝炎
We're gonna get hepatitis just breathing the air.
就是这里  韦德以前住的地方
This is it. It's where Wade used to live.
破烂的家
Home crack home.
别管我
Leave me alone!
别来烦我
I don't want you here.
-纽约警察  -谁来救救我
- N.Y.P.D. - Somebody help me.
-警察  -警察  不许动
- Police! - N.Y.P.D.! Don't move!
本杰明·韦德  你涉嫌谋杀被逮捕了
Benjamin Wade, you're under arrest for murder.
认得她吗  韦德先生
Recognize her, mr. Wade?
这是你跟踪她的照片
And this is you, stalking her
就在她被杀之前
shortly before she was killed.
可以解释一下吗
You care to explain?
也许他立誓保持沉默了
Maybe he took a vow of silence.
沉默而凶狠
You know, silent but deadly.
前提是他真的是个修道士
Assuming he's a real monk.
事实上  我是修道士
Actually, I am a monk.
我只是学会了言前三思
I've just learned to think before I speak.
我出狱以后皈依了
I joined the Franciscan Order of Perpetual Hope
永福圣方济会
after I left prison.
你皈依的这家修道院
This monastery that you're a part of--
是不是正好在华盛顿高地呢
does it happen to be in Washington Heights?
我们就是在那里发现了苏珊娜·里奇兰德的尸体
Because that's exactly where we found Susannah Richland,
考虑到你的前科
And given your record--
我已经重新做人了
Not that guy anymore.
患脑瘤后  我获得了心灵上的觉悟
After my brain tumor, I had a spiritual awakening.
找到了人生的意义
Found a purpose.
那你在那烂房子里干什么
Then what were you doing in a crack house?
我是在照顾那些迷途的羔羊
I was tending to the lost.
我不是在跟踪这个女人
Wasn't stalking this woman. I was...
而是想保护她
I was trying to protect her.
保护她
Protect her?
我在修道礼堂里看到她
I found her in a monastery chapel.
她跪在祷告蜡烛旁边
She was kneeling by the prayer candles.
说这地方对她家有特殊意义
Said the place was special to her family.
于是我让她独自一人静静祷告
So I left her to pray in peace,
然后有人来了  棕色长发  戴眼镜
and this guy shows up-- brown long hair, glasses.
戴着帽子  向我打听那个女人
He's wearing this hat. Starts asking me questions about her.
想知道她在里面干什么  他很生气
Wants to know what she's doing there. He's upset.
看起来咄咄逼人
He seems aggressive.
韦德先生  是你在跟踪她
Mr. Wade, that's you following her,
可不是别的什么人
not some other guy.
我以为他会对她下手
I thought that he was gonna go after her.
所以我才跟着她  直到她上了计程车
So I did. I followed her until she got into a cab,
然后我就回到修道院
and then I came back to the monastery.
真的吗
Really?
好呀
Okay.
描述一下计程车吧
Describe the cab.
就是辆计程车而已
It was a cab.
车牌号  计程车号
License plate. Medallion number.
我不记得了  好像是辆
I don't remember. It was a...
丰田普锐斯吧
Prius, maybe.
这车可有好几百辆呢
There are hundreds of those.
会讲故事的人善于运用细节
A good storyteller uses details.
这样谎话才编得圆
It's what sells the lie.
我没撒谎  车顶有音乐剧《女巫前传》的广告
It's not a lie. There was an ad for "Wicked" on top of it.
《女巫前传》
"Wicked."
不错  很到位  泄露内心的小细节
That's nice. It's precise. Freudian little detail.
但仍是谎言
But still a lie.
有一点他倒没撒谎
So here's what's not a lie.
我给方济会打了电话
Just called the Franciscan Order.
本杰明·韦德的确是个修道士
Turns out Benjamin Wade really is a monk.
还是本案凶手
And our murderer.
只要能找到证据就好
Now we just need to prove it.
慢着  你俩对这个人看法一致
Wait. You guys are on the same page about this guy?
不完全一致  我认为他有罪
Not exactly. I think he's guilty
是因为他和被害人有关联
because of his contact with the victim,
他跟踪了她  外加他还有暴力史
the stalking, and his history of violence.
而我认为他有罪是因为他和被害人有关联
I think he's guilty because of his contact with the victim,
他跟踪了她  外加他还卷入了一桩
the stalking, and his role in a sinister conspiracy
和共济会有关的危险阴谋
involving freemasons.
我不敢相信你以为那封信是真的
I can't believe you're really buying into that letter.
你不相信才奇怪呢
I can't believe you aren't.
我调查了一下那封信的作者
I did a little research into the author of our letter--
西奥多·罗斯先生
Mr. Theodore Rose.
你知不知道他曾是共济会最高级长老
Did you know he was a 33rd degree master mason?
也就是说他是共济会的黑带级人物
So that makes him, what, like a freemason black belt?
比那还厉害  他是一位爱国间谍
Way better than that. He was a patriot spy.
他在独立战争时用密码和暗语传递信息
He wrote codes and ciphers during the American Revolution,
这就意味着这封信是找到
meaning this letter could be the key to finding
共济会至高机密的关键
the great secret of the masons,
而这机密就封存在这座城市里
enshrined somewhere within the city.
为啥  因为你巴不得这是真的
Why? Because you want it to be?
有点吧  再就是因为
Partly, and because
只有这套理论能解释得通
it's the only story that makes sense.
神秘兄弟会要确保罗斯的秘密
Shadowy brotherhood guarding Rose's secret
永不见天日
for all eternity.
苏珊娜查得太深
Susannah got too close,
所以他们派出修道士刺客杀她灭口
so they sent their monk assassin to kill her.
说到这  韦德的律师来了
Yeah, about that--uh, Wade's lawyer's here.
他说我们要么起诉  要么放人
He says we need to charge his client or let him go.
我们没有足够证据起诉他
We don't have enough to charge him.
不如先拖住他  等证据充足再说
Why don't we try to keep him until we do?
让韦德去见素描师
Put Wade in with a sketch artist.
让他描述一下
Have him describe that guy
他声称跟踪苏珊娜的那人的样貌
that was supposedly stalking Susannah.
这样我和卡塞尔就有足够时间
That'll buy Castle and I enough time
去戳穿他的不在场证明
to tear his alibi apart,
另外为谨慎起见
and just to cover our bases,
你去查一下韦德说的那辆出租车
you look into that cab that wade described.
说真的  你想让我追查一辆
Really? You want me to track down a cab
顶着《女巫前传》广告的出租车
off a banner ad for "Wicked"?
让我开开眼
Impress me.
有时候我真希望她待在特区别回来
You know, there are times I wish she stayed in D.C.
抱歉  探长  但你的确弄错了
I'm sorry, detective, but you're wrong.
在这位年轻女士遇害的时段里
Brother Benjamin was in his quarters at the time you say
本杰明修士确实待在他的住处
this young woman was killed.
有什么人能证明吗
And can anyone else verify that?
至少有七位本会成员看见他了
At least seven other members of our order saw him.
你们的使命究竟是什么
And... what exactly is the mission of your order?
帮助有需要的人
To care for those in need,
遵循并分享基督的教诲
to live by and share the teachings of Christ.
我认为你
I think you
忘了说"保卫惊天秘密"那部分了
left out the part about protecting a great secret.
恐怕我没明白您的意思
I'm afraid I don't understand.
装傻吗
Don't you?
我真没听明白
No, I don't.
那个  感谢你抽时间见我们
Uh... thank you... so much for your time.
"感谢你抽时间见我们"  这就完事了
"Thank you for your time"? That's it?
没错  直到我们拿到
Yeah, until we get the statements
那七个证人的证词
from the seven other witnesses.
听着  他们肯定口径一致
Look, they're all gonna tell you the same thing.
还不明白吗
Don't you see?
这些修道士  心往一块想  劲往一处使
These monks--they're in it up to their hoods.
除非  他们并非在保护这个秘密
Unless... unless they're not protecting the great secret
而是也在找寻它
and they're actually trying to find it, too.
因为  就像约柜一样
Because, like the ark of the covenant,
这个秘密是终极能量源
it is a source of ultimate power.
卡塞尔  这些修道士全都
Castle, these monks took vows
立下清贫  禁欲  服从之誓
of poverty, chastity, and obedience.
我可不认为他们图谋统治世界
I don't see them trying to take over the world.
世界
World.
怎么了
What?
西奥多·罗斯写的那封信
Theodore Rose's letter.
拉丁文写的线索
There was that one clue in latin. Uh...
"世界在天堂与埃土间翻转"
"The world turns between the heavens and the ash heap."
拉丁语中"埃土"这个词
In latin, the word for "Ash heap"
又指"祭坛"
also means "Altar."
那扇彩窗描绘的是天堂
The heavens are depicted in that stained glass.
那么祭坛肯定就在它下面
And the altar is right underneath it.
这些线索指引她到这里  但原因何在
So the clues led her to this chapel, but why?
那些祈祷蜡烛
The prayer candles.
这里肯定就是韦德说他发现
So this must be where Wade
苏珊娜跪祷的地方了
said he found Susannah kneeling.
卡塞尔  看这里
Castle, look.
有纹理刻在基座上
There's something carved in that base stone.
那就是她画在手上的图案
That's the symbol she drew on her hand.
那其它的线索
So these other clues...
肯定指向其它藏有这类图案的地点
Must lead to other places where the symbols are hidden.
-但这些图案又有什么意义  -听这段
- But what are they for? - Listen to this.
"无论天神凡人  皆难御神匠之击"
"For gods and men alike doth lame Hephaestus strike."
我明白了  我知道在哪了
I know what that means. I know where that is.
-你明白了  -没错  赫菲斯托斯
- You do? - Yeah. Hephaestus was
是希腊神话中的铁匠之神
the Greek god of blacksmiths.
他的熔铁炉就在埃特纳火山
His forge was in Mount Etna.
下曼哈顿区就有家老铁匠铺
There's an old blacksmith's shop right here in Lower Manhattan
名字就叫"埃特纳熔炉"
called Etna's Forge.
18世纪起就在那了
It's been there since the 1700s.
我知道是因为我和阿丽克西斯去过那
I know because I was there with... Alexis.
她三年级的实地考察  但肯定错不了
It was... A field trip. Third grade, but that-- that's gotta be it.
被害人是被剑刺死的
Our victim was killed with a sword.
如果那家老铁匠铺真的存在
If there's an old blacksmith shop,
没准凶杀现场就在那
that could be our crime scene.
一条人们为其厮杀的
A clue trail to a freemason secret
共济会秘密线索
that people would kill for--
这案子越来越有趣了
This case just keeps getting better.
或许本杰明·韦德那天夜里其实
So maybe what Benjamin Wade actually did that night
是跟踪苏珊娜到了铁匠铺
was follow Susannah to this blacksmith shop.
卡塞尔  我们还不知道她是否来过这里
Castle, we don't even know if she was here.
她肯定来过
Oh, she was here, all right,
马上就要解开谜团
on the verge of solving the puzzle
却在此时不幸早逝
when her life was cut tragically short.
就是这里
This is the place.
我从来不知道这里还有个铁匠铺
I never knew this was here.
太不可思议了
Wow, this is incredible.
不是应该有个讲解员
Shouldn't there be a... docent
或者满头大汗的人站在这里打铁吗
or some sweaty guy hammering metal standing around?
是啊
Yeah.
有人吗
Hello?!
这里有铁匠吗
Is there a smithy hereabouts?
我们千里迢迢来……
We have traveled many a mile to the--
这样很讨厌吗
Is this annoying?
是的  这样吧  我去后面查看一下
Yeah. You know what? I'm gonna check in back.
你在这里四处看看
Why don't you take a look around here?
如果这是我们要找的犯罪现场
If this is our crime scene,
可能会有挣扎的痕迹
there might be signs of struggle.
好
Right.
这个有了
Have it...
这个想要
Want it...
这个需要
Need it...
有了  需要
Got it... need it...
你不应该来这里寻找符号
You should not have come here looking for the sign,
因为等待你的只有死亡
for only death awaits you.
那个
Well, now...
你手里的不会刚好是一把有雉堞的
That wouldn't happen to be a double-edged saber
双刃佩剑吧
with a crenelated hilt, now, would it?
你已闯入你无法理解的秘密
You have trespassed into secrets beyond your comprehension.
你将用生命为此付出代价
You will pay with your life.
好吧  在你杀我之前
Okay. O-okay, b-but just... before you kill me,
有件事是你应该知道
there's one thing you should know.
什么事
And what is that?
我很擅长剑术
I am really good at this.
你也不差
Uhh! You're not so bad yourself.
你是谁
Who are you?
关于西奥多·罗斯遗愿  你知道些什么
And what do you know about the last will of Theodore Rose?
两百年来我们守护着这个秘密
For 200 years, my people have guarded that secret.
这个秘密将被带进我的坟墓  或者你的
It will go with me to my grave... or yours!
你是谁
Now who are you?
我是谁不重要
It's not important who I am.
你赢了  符号应被揭晓
The win is yours. The sign shall be revealed.
那是苏珊娜白板上的符号
That's the symbol from Susannah's board.
她来过这里  是你
She was here. It was you.
是你杀了她
You're the one who killed her.
等等  你赢了  哥们儿
Whoa, wait a minute. You won, man.
你现在可以把剑放下了
You can put the sword down now.
除非你告诉我你是谁
Not until you tell me who you are
还有你为什么要杀死苏珊娜·里奇兰德  贝克特
and why you killed Susannah Richland. Beckett!
我觉得你好像搞错了
I think there's been some kind of mistake here.
不不不  没搞错
No, no, no, no mistake.
苏珊娜被你或你们这伙人中的一个
Susannah was stabbed through the throat
用一柄双刃佩剑刺穿喉咙
with a double-edged saber by you or one of your people.
对不起  我有点迷糊了
I'm sorry. I'm a little lost here.
他们改剧本了吗
Did they change the script?
因为如果他们改了  他们可没告诉我
'cause if they did, they didn't tell me.
剧本
Script?
什么剧本
What script?
寻宝游戏
The scavenger hunt.
卡塞尔
Castle?
怎么回事
What's going on?
寻宝游戏
A scavenger hunt?
这些线索  符号  都是个游戏吗
So the clues, the symbol-- it's all just a game?
是为纽约历史研究院举办的募捐
It's a fund-raiser for the New York Historical Institute.
线索指引到历史建筑
The clues lead to historic buildings,
参加游戏的人在里面收集这些古老符号
where the players collect these old symbols.
他们雇佣像我这样的演员与参赛者互动
They hire actors like me to interact with the contestants.
我通常在文艺复兴集市上演出
I usually work Renaissance Fairs.
这个女人是你们的参赛者之一吗
Was this woman one of your contestants?
是  她几天前就过了这一关
Yeah. She came through here couple days ago.
她被杀害了吗
She was killed?
是  被一柄佩剑
Yeah, with a saber
跟你用的这把几乎一模一样
almost exactly like the one you were using.
那是特技武器  不会伤人  这些都是
That was a stunt weapon. It's harmless. They all are.
我没杀人  我只是个演员
I didn't kill anybody. I'm just an actor.
我昨晚都没在这里工作
I wasn't even working here last night.
拜托  打电话给纽约历史研究所
Look, please, call the New York Historical Institute.
找他们的主管诺兰·伯恩斯
Talk to Nolan Burns, their director.
这全都是游戏而已
This is all just a game.
这当然只是个游戏
Of course it was just a game.
每年越来越多的纽约历史建筑
Every year, more and more historic New York buildings
被拆毁
are being torn down,
作为历史研究所的主管
and as director of the Historical Institute,
我在寻找有趣的方式来提高关注度
I was looking for a fun way to raise awareness.
伯恩斯先生  这些
Mr. Burns, these symbols
苏珊娜·里奇兰德拍下照片的符号
that Susannah Richland took pictures of--
也是游戏的一部分吗
are those also a part of the game?
是的  这些都是用在游戏中的符号
Yes, these are all... symbols used in the game.
看来她找到了全部
Looks like she found them all.
她本有可能胜出的
She might have won.
有没有可能是有人为了赢得比赛
Is it possible that someone would have killed her
而杀了她
to get a competitive edge?
奖金是2500美元
Prize money is $2,500.
一些参赛者的路费都比这多
Some of the contestants spent more than that in travel expenses.
这些符号可能有别的意思吗
Could these symbols mean something else?
带有危险性的意思
Something dangerous?
据我所知没有
Not that I'm aware of.
我知道在一些18世纪建造的房子上
I do know they can be found on buildings
能找到这些符号
dating as far back as the 1700s,
所以我才使用了它们
which is why I used them.
但是
It's just...
被害人身上带着一封信
Our victim had this letter on her.
出自18世纪共济会成员西奥多·罗斯之手
It's from an 18th-century freemason named Theodore Rose.
他在信中提到一个巨大的隐秘
In it, he speaks of a great hidden secret.
"藏在这座城市之中"
It'd be "Enshrined in the city."
这封信是游戏的一部分
The letter was part of the game.
我们把它手写在羊皮纸上
We had it hand-written on parchment.
参赛者人手一份
One for each contestant.
但罗斯确有其人
But Rose is real.
他热衷于留下线索和密码
He had a penchant for clues and ciphers.
正是如此  他增加了游戏的真实性
Exactly. He brought some authenticity.
他是一名共济会成员
And the fact that he was a freemason
又是乔治·华盛顿之友的事实
and a friend of George Washington's
让他成为本游戏核心人物的最佳人选
made rose the perfect person on whom to base the game.
所以我从他的手稿提取部分内容
So I drew from his writings,
剩下的则从共济会历史中摘取
and the rest I pulled from freemason history.
但这都是虚构的
But none of this is real.
我从未想到这会导致某人的死亡
I don't see how any of this would lead to someone's death.
不管怎样  我需要所有参赛者的姓名
Regardless, I'm gonna need the names of all of the contestants.
那你得联系这次活动的策划公司
You'll have to check with the event planning company,
"极限游戏"  他们负责活动报名
Games Ultra. They handled the registration.
无法相信费这么大劲最后竟都是虚构的
Can't believe all this time, it was all just make-believe.
卡塞尔  你不是真的相信
Castle, you didn't really believe
这背后隐藏着一个
that this was gonna lead to some
共济会宝藏  是吧
great freemason treasure, did you?
不  当然不相信  那太傻了
No, of course not. That'd be foolish.
我先失陪了  我要回家
Now if you'll excuse me, I'm gonna go home
沉溺于我破案生涯中
to wallow in what is perhaps the most disappointing day
最令人失望的一天中  暗自抹泪
Of my crime-solving career.
我过会回去  给你打打气
Okay, I'll come by later and try to cheer you up.
从"极限游戏"那拿到参赛者名单了么
Did we get the list of contestants from Games Ultra?
拿到了  而且参赛报名表
Yep, and the contestant applications
肯定会有照片  看看这位老兄
had to include a photo. Take a look at this dude.
他怎么了
What about him?
与修道士提供的跟踪苏珊娜的
Well, check out the sketch that our monk gave us of the guy
家伙的素描对比下
that he says was following Susannah.
是同一个人
Well, it's the same guy.
那关于这位汤姆·史蒂文斯
Okay. So... what do we know
我们知道些什么
about Tom Stevens?
他的名字和地址都是伪造的
Well, his name and address are bogus.
报名表上的其他信息也一样
Everything on the application is.
没一条是真的
None of this information is real.
他肯定就是凶手
And he had to be the guy who killed her.
他到过修道院
He was at the monastery.
不然怎么会用假名注册
Why else would he sign up with a fake name?
他的名字是假的  但他的钱是真的
Well, his name might be fake, but his money is real.
找到了  支票付款
And there you go. Paid with a check.
如果我们能查到这次付款
If we can trace that payment...
那我们就能知道他是谁
Then we might be able to I.D. him.
看看"极限游戏"在哪家银行开户
All right, see where Games Ultra keeps their accounts
明早立刻联系那家银行
and hit that bank first thing in the morning.
我要找到这家伙
I want this guy found.
理查德
Richard?
Richard.
抱歉  什么事
I'm sorry. What?
这是些什么
What is all this?
只是些  游戏
Oh, just some... game.
你最好抽点时间
Well, you might wanna
关注下现实世界
pay attention to the real world for a moment.
阿丽克西斯对你在那天晚上聚餐时的行为
Alexis is furious with you over your behavior
极为恼火  我必须说  我赞成她
at dinner the other night, and I must say, I agree.
得了  我没那么糟糕
Come on. It wasn't that bad.
你羞辱了她的公寓
You insulted her apartment.
你拿她男友的工作开玩笑
You made fun of her boyfriend's career.
老妈  他在数蜜蜂
Mother, he's counting bees.
是的  而且那对他很重要
Yes, and it is important to him,
正如阿丽克西斯对他很重要
As Alexis is important to him.
我就是不明白  她怎么会和他在一起
I just don't even understand. Why is she even with him?
这是她想要的
This is what she wants.
她下个周下个月想要什么
Now will she want it next week or next month?
谁知道
Who knows?
但这是她此时此刻想要的
But this is what she wants today.
如果你想要她融入你的生活
And if you want her to be a part of your life,
那你必须改变看问题的角度
then you are going to have to change your point of view.
你是对的  老妈
You're right, mother.
我当然是对的  好极了
Of course I'm right. Good.
看问题的角度
Point of view...
这不是场游戏
This isn't a game.
完全不是
This isn't a game at all.
没找到
No luck.
根据银行记录
According to the bank,
史蒂文斯先生确实用支票付的款
Mr. Stevens did pay with a check,
但那是张银行本票  无法追踪
but it was a cashier's check, so there's no way to trace it.
隐瞒身份
Hiding his identity,
在被害人死前跟踪她
following our victim just before she died.
他肯定就是凶手
This has gotta be our killer.
我终于追踪到了被害人上的
Okay. I finally tracked down that cab
那辆出租
that our victim got into--
车顶有《女巫前传》广告的那辆
The one with the "Wicked" banner ad on top.
开始  我打电话给
So first, I had to call
《女巫前传》上演的剧院
the theater Where "Wicked" Was playing.
他们把我指向公关公司
They directed me to a P.R. firm who then
然后又让我去找广告中介
sent me to an ad agency
他们代理出租车顶的广告  然后五辆车
that sells space on the top of cabs, and five cabs--
-你跟出租车司机谈了没  -嗯
- Did you talk to the cabbie or not? - Yes.
问到了  出租车司机确认他载过苏珊娜
Yes, I did. The cabbie confirmed that he picked up Susannah
晚上10:10在华盛顿高地
in Washington heights at 10:10 P.M.
看来修道士说的是实话
So our monk was telling the truth.
那出租车司机把她载到哪了
Okay, where did the cabbie take her?
奇怪的是  他没载她去任何地方
That's the odd part. He didn't take her anywhere.
-什么意思  -苏珊娜只是让他
- What do you mean? - Susannah just had him
在附近绕了45分钟
drive around the neighborhood for 45 minutes
然后回到教堂把她放下车
and dropped her back off at the chapel.
这说不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
为什么她当晚又回去了
Why would she go back there the same night?
我来告诉你为什么
I'll tell you why.
因为苏珊娜发现这不只是个游戏
Because Susannah realized it wasn't just a game.
卡塞尔  别告诉我你还在...
Castle, please don't tell me that you're still on--
不不  听我说
Oh, no, no. Just listen.
伯恩斯告诉我们  他把游戏设定在
Burns told us that he based the game
西奥多·罗斯的一些作品之上
on some of the writings of Theodore Rose.
如果罗斯给的提示都是真的呢
Now what if Rose's clues were real
真的能指向某个地方
and actually led somewhere?
如果苏珊娜发现了这一点呢
What if Susannah figured that out?
这是所有的符号
Here are all our symbols.
互相之间看似没有关联
They didn't seem to relate to each other
直到加上这一块  苏珊娜画在她手上的这块
until you add this one--the one Susannah drew on her hand.
她当晚在教堂发现这符号后就被杀了
The one she found at the chapel the night she was killed.
它们可以拼合起来
They all fit together.
最后一块  没有它  其他的都拼不起来
Final piece. Without it, the others didn't fit.
所以凶手把她手上符号的抹掉了
That's why the killer scraped it off her hand.
他不希望她或者其他人
He didn't want her or anyone else
发现这个秘密
to be able to figure it out.
那么碎片拼起来之后
Okay, so the pieces fit together.
能说明什么呢
What do they mean?
我不知道  但是...
I don't know, but...
这个形状看着眼熟吗
Does this shape look familiar?
眼熟
Yes, it does.
-好神奇  -是啊
- Amazing, right? - Yeah.
但这能说明什么呢
But what does it mean?
说明这不是游戏的一部分
It means that this isn't a part of any game.
如果所有符号拼合之后指向这个浮雕
If all those symbols put together indicate this carving,
那它一定内含玄机
then it has to have some kind of significance.
卡塞尔  看这个
Castle, look at this.
每个符号旁边都有一个小字母
Each one of these symbols has a small letter next to it--
R-O-S-I
R-O-S-I.
罗西  可能是指他的名字罗斯
Rosi? Maybe it's supposed to be his name--Rose.
这是"I"
Uh, that's a-- that's an "I".
可能是"Rois"  法语中的"国王"
Um... maybe it's "Rois", Like, uh, french for "King,"
"Soir"  法语中的"夜晚"
Or, uh, "Soir" For "Evening".
不  等等
Oh, no, wait.
土  气  水  火  以太在中央
Earth, air, water, fire, ether in the center.
在中世纪炼金术中代表五大元素
In medieval alchemy, these are the five elements
它们组成了宇宙
that make up the universe,
但它们的重要性有先后之分
But there's an order of importance--
土  气  水  火
Earth, air, water, fire.
把字母按照这个顺序排列
We put the letters in that order,
那就是O-R-I
It's O-R-I...
S
S.
"Oris"
"Oris".
拉丁语中的"口"
Latin for "Mouth."
-我开玩笑呢  -卡塞尔
- I'm just kidding. - Castle!
没想到你会上当
I can't believe you fell for that.
不过里面真的有东西  等等
There is something in here, though. Hang on.
苏珊娜来过这里
Susannah was here.
这里是犯罪现场
This is our crime scene.
这是凶器
There's our murder weapon.
卡塞尔  看这里  这些痕迹是新的
Castle, look at this. These marks are fresh.
有人想把它打开
Someone was trying to get inside it.
苏珊娜当晚肯定来过
Susannah must have come to the chapel that night
和我们一样发现了进来的方法
and figured out how to get in here just like we did.
不过在打开石棺前
Except the killer found her
凶手找到了她
before she was able to open the sarcophagus.
你觉得里面是什么
What do you think's inside?
不知道
I don't know,
有人觉得里面放着值得去杀人的东西
but someone thought it was worth killing for.
好吧
Okay.
推...推不动
Okay, okay.
如果跟我们先前推理的一样
Okay. If it's like everything else we've been doing,
解开线索才能打开它
we need to solve a clue to open it.
卡塞尔  看这个地球
Hey, Castle, look at the world.
跟圣坛上的彩色玻璃那个看上去一样
It's just like the one in the stained glass above the altar.
"世界在天堂与埃土间翻转"
"The world spins between the heavens and the ash heap."
尘归尘  石棺也许就代表埃土
Ashes to ashes. The coffin could be the ash heap.
这就表示  那么
Which means, then, that...
那儿  那里是天堂
There. Those are heavens.
"地球翻转"
"The world turns..."
"1792年"
"1792".
这是拜福德教授跟我们说过的
These are the half dimes Professor Byford
五美分银币
just told us about.
这些是美国财政部铸造的
These are the very first coins
第一批硬币
to be minted by the U.S. Treasury.
可值钱了
These are worth a fortune.
杀人动机也有了
Now we have our motive for murder.
去年拍卖会上  一枚就值
Just one of these went for auction last year.
150万美元
$1.5 million.
这里应该有一千枚
There's gotta be a thousand of them in here.
你知道这得值多少钱吗
Do you have any idea what that's worth?
我已经告诉你了
I just told you what it's worth.
怎么回事
What was that?
要我猜  肯定不是好事
If I had to guess, I would say something bad.
不  不
No, no.
卡塞尔  把那袋硬币放回棺材里
Castle, put the bag of coins back in the coffin.
也许门会再打开
Maybe it'll open up the door again.
好主意
Good idea.
该死
Rats.
在我的想象中  带你来教堂可不是这个样子
This is not my idea of going to the chapel with you.
你手机有信号吗
Do you have a cell signal?
没有
Yeah, it doesn't look like it.
看来那封信上说的没错
Well, then the letter was right.
"若心生歹意
"Peril and woe to him who follows this path
必将遭遇不幸"  咱们死定了
with a dark heart." This is it.
卡塞尔  咱们不会死在这的
Castle, we're not gonna die in here.
你也看到那些墙有多厚了
You saw how thick those walls were.
那都是石头墙  我们就算是大喊大叫一整天
They're made of stone. We can yell and scream
也不会有人听得见的
all day long. No one's gonna hear.
这屋里又不可能有吃的
It's not like they stocked up this place with supplies.
等咱俩吃蜡烛吃够了以后怎么办
And what's gonna happen when we get tired of eating candle wax?
不会的  我们会从这里出去的
No, we're gonna get out of here.
肯定有办法出去的
There has to be a way out.
好吧  也许你是对的
Okay, yeah, you know what? You're right.
这只是西奥多·罗斯对我们的考验
All right, this is just Theodore Rose testing us.
肯定还会有其它线索  其它的谜题
There's gotta be another clue, another puzzle.
有可能是跟他的名字有关  会不会
Something to do with his name. What if...
会不会是变位词呢
what if it's an anagram?
西奥多·罗斯还可以拼成
Theodore Rose...is...
留意或是脚趾
heed or toes.
不对  西奥多·罗斯还可以是
No. Theodore Rose...
他  干公鸡
he...do rooster.
这太不合适了  好吧
That's inappropriate. Okay.
西奥多·罗斯  西奥多·罗斯
Theodore Rose, Theodore Rose.
鹿吃奥利奥
Deer shot Oreo.
十八世纪还没有奥利奥呢
Oh, they didn't have Oreos in the 1700s.
-卡塞尔  可能有别的办法出去  -我洗耳恭听
- Castle, there might be another way out of here. - I'm all ears.
杀害苏珊娜的凶手知道
Susannah's killer knows that the half dimes
这些五美分硬币还在这
are still in here.
他早晚得回到这里来
Eventually, he's gonna have to come back...
取走这些硬币
to get them.
他肯定是一个一开始就知道硬币存在的人
He must be somebody who knew they existed in the first place.
一个一开始就知道这一切都是
Someone...who knew...all of this...
真实的人
was real.
还有谁比那个让大家都以为这只是个游戏的人
And who better than the person who wanted everyone to think
更可疑的呢
that this was just a game?
诺兰·伯恩斯
Nolan Burns.
历史研究院的主管
The director of the historical institute.
卡塞尔  我手机有信号了
Castle, I've got bars.
终于啊
Finally.
怎么了  贝克特
What's up, Beckett?
埃斯波  你得马上来教堂一下
Espo, you need to get to the chapel now.
还有  让莱恩把诺兰·伯恩斯带回局里
And tell Ryan to pick up Nolan Burns.
伯恩斯先生
Mr. Burns...
上次见你的时候  你漏了一些细节没有告诉我们
you left out a few details the last time we spoke.
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
你找到了
You found them.
所以说这不仅仅是个游戏
So it wasn't just a game.
的确
No.
我们发给选手们的信件
That...letter we gave the contestants
是以真实的信件为基础改写的
was based on an actual letter
而那封信是我在重新装修研究院时找到的
I found hidden in the building I was renovating.
我本来  是打算自己解开那些线索的
I tried to...follow the clues myself,
可是我有几个搞不懂的
but I couldn't solve them all.
于是你就设计了这么一个寻宝游戏
You set up a scavenger hunt to solve clues
想通过众人的力量来解谜
through crowdsourcing.
我从没想过会有人受伤
I never thought anyone would get hurt.
不是受伤  伯恩斯  是被杀害
Not hurt, Burns. Murdered.
但不是我干的  我发誓
But not by me, I swear.
我  我告诉过你  她去世的那天晚上
I-I told you, I-I was at home with my family
我在家里陪我的家人
the night she died.
你还跟我说你不认识苏珊娜呢
You also told me that you didn't know Susannah.
我跟你的助手聊过了
I spoke with your assistant.
你在三个月前见过苏珊娜
You met with her three months ago.
这件事你怎么能不告诉我们呢
How did you fail to mention that?
因为我知道你们会怎么想
'Cause I knew how it would look!
现在情况对你更不利了
And now it looks even worse.
你为什么要见她
Now why did you meet with her?
因为我希望她能在罗斯的家族史上
Because I hoped she would shed some light
给我点提示
on the Rose family history.
没准能找到一些可以帮助我解开最后一道谜题的东西
You know, something that might help solve that last clue,
仅此而已
but that was it!
等一下  倒回去一下
Wait a minute. Go back.
苏珊娜只是个会计
Susannah was an accountant.
她怎么会了解罗斯家族呢
Why would she know anything about the Rose family?
因为她是西奥多·罗斯的
Because she was a direct descendant
直系后代
of Theodore Rose.
失踪的五美分的传说
The legend of the missing half dimes
是他们的家族传说
was family lore.
家族传说
Family lore.
我听说你们在我表妹的谋杀案上
Hey. They said you found something out
有所进展
about my cousin's murder.
是的  不过我们要先跟你核对一些事情
Uh, we did. We, uh, we just need to go over a few things first.
根据她的通话记录
Now according to her phone records,
她上几个月跟你联系的比以往频繁
she called you more frequently over the last few months.
有什么特别原因吗
Is there any reason why?
我觉得她是一个人寂寞了
I got the feeling she was lonely.
她有提到过西奥多·罗斯吗
A-and did she ever mention Theodore Rose?
没有  她提这个干吗
No. Why would she?
这么说你了解失踪的五美分的传说咯
So you're familiar with the lore of the missing half dimes?
当然  这是个家族之谜
Yeah, sure. It was a big family myth.
只不过事实并非如此
Except it wasn't.
苏珊娜还真找到了那些硬币
Susannah actually located the coins.
它们被藏在教堂的密室里  她就是因此被杀的
They were in a hidden crypt. That's where she was killed.
太可怕了
That's terrible.
知道是谁干的吗
Do you know who did it?
最有可能的是知道她在寻宝的人
Most likely someone who knew what she was looking for.
鉴证组在密室里找到两组DNA
CSU Found two sets of DNA in that crypt.
一组是苏珊娜的  另一组是凶手的
One was from Susannah. One was from her killer.
我凭直觉找人对比了一下两组DNA
Now on a hunch, I had them compare the two,
结果显示  杀死苏珊娜的凶手
and the results indicate that Susannah and her killer
与她有血缘关系
were related.
鉴证组还发现了一根假发丝
CSU also found a synthetic hair
它属于类似这样的假发
found in a wig not unlike this one.
你使用假名  报名参加了寻宝游戏
You signed up for the game under a false name.
乔装打扮  来查探她的进度
You used a disguise so you could track her progress.
一切都结束了亨利  你就是凶手
It's over, Henry. We know it's you.
我妈妈住在疗养院
My mom's in assisted living.
我努力工作  但还是过得非常拮据
I work hard, but I barely get by.
那些银币能改变我的人生
Those half dimes were gonna change my life.
但苏珊娜却说找到它们以后
But Susannah said that she was gonna find them
要把它们全捐出去
and then just give them all away.
她说那是历史的遗物
Said they were part of history,
属于人民
that they belonged to the people.
那晚  她打电话跟我说她找到了
She called me that night with the good news,
我再次试着阻止她把它们捐出去
and I tried to talk her out of it one last time.
我们发生争执
We argued.
之后就...
And the next thing I knew...
我查了之前的记录
Well, I was looking through the records,
发现有好几代罗斯家的人
and I found out there have been
都是在那所教堂举行的婚礼
several Rose family weddings in that chapel.
苏珊娜几年前也曾去过那里
Susannah had even been there once years ago.
她一定还记得见过那扇琉璃彩窗
She must have remembered seeing that stained glass window.
所以只有她能明白最后的线索
That's how she was able to figure out that last clue
所蕴含的意义
when no one else could.
也是亨利把她手上的记号挖去的原因
And why Henry scraped it off her hand,
确保除了他没人能发现银币
so he could be only one that'd ever find it.
那些银币怎么处理
So what's gonna happen to the half dimes?
银币是在教堂被发现的
Well, they were found in the chapel,
所以属于修道院
so they belong to the monastery.
和尚们的誓言遇到试炼了
Well, that'll put the monks' vow of poverty to the test.
他们已经已满分通过了"试炼"
They've already passed that with flying colors.
因为那些银币是重要的历史遗物
Because of the historical significance of the coins,
所以全都捐给大都会艺术博物馆
they're donating them to The Met.
你们知道吗
You know...
又来了  我先走了
Here we go. I gotta go.
历史上传说  这些银币是乔治·华盛顿
It is believed that George Washington
将玛莎·华盛顿的银饰熔化后铸成的
had those half dimes minted from Martha Washington's silver.
那时候  在独立革命之前
Back then, before the revolution,
除了国王  其他人私自铸币是违法的
it was illegal for anyone but a king to mint money.
所以  这些银币的价值远超过它们本身
So those coins are worth a lot more than just their silver.
它们实际上是美国独立的宣言
They're actually more of a declaration of independence.
那就对了
Well, then it's right
像苏珊娜希望的那样回归人民
That they're going back to the people,
是物归原主了
like Susannah wanted.
说到"独立"  我得去找阿丽克西斯
Speaking of independence, I gotta go see Alexis.
能进来吗
Can I come in?
就在这说吧
We can talk here.
我对之前的行为感到非常抱歉
Look, I'm... sorry about how I acted.
抱歉也不够
Being sorry isn't enough, dad.
那我该怎么做
Then what can I do?
我要怎么做你才能原谅我
What can I do to make this right?
你知道我是怎么得知你像贝克特求婚的事的吗
Do you know how I found out you had proposed to Beckett?
在哥斯达黎加  奶奶打电话告诉我的
Over the phone with gram while I was in Costa Rica.
是因为贝克特的事吗
This is about Beckett?
不  但你没告诉我  使我很难过
No, but I was hurt you didn't tell me.
我是有打算要告诉你的
Look, I was going to tell you.
只是...
It just...
事情发生得太突然
It just happened.
的确  而且我也不确定那是个好主意
I know it did, and I don't know if it's a good idea
不确定她就是你的真命天女
or if she's really the one,
但我还是接受了  不是吗
but you know what? I accept it.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
因为她让你开心
Because she makes you happy,
就像派让我开心一样
the same way Pi makes me happy.
我所要求的不过是我给予你的
All I want is the same thing I'm giving you--
无条件的接受
acceptance.
好吧  我接受他
Okay. I accept him.
不  你才没有接受
No, you don't.
嘴上怎么说不重要
Because it's not about what you say.
心里的认同才算数
It's what's inside.
我知道  你心里还是抗拒的
I know what's there now,
我不想派感觉到你的抗拒
and I don't want Pi to feel that from you,
我也不想自己为此不开心
and... I don't wanna feel that either.
听着
Look...
我会试着接受
I'll work on it.
我会的
I will.
与此同时  我们能不能一起去吃个雪糕
Meantime, how about we go out for some makeup ice cream?
好不好  我请客
Okay? My treat.
不好
No.
我需要时间冷静下来
I need time to stop being mad,
你也需要时间学习
and you need time to figure out a way
怎么接受这一切
to be okay with this.
回见  爸爸
I'll see you later, dad.